[Music]
[âm nhạc]
Commemorating the Buddha's birth, we follow
kỷ niệm ngày Đức Phật đàn sinh chúng con
in his footsteps, rejoicing in the
theo bước chân từng đoạn nhiều mừng Đức
Buddha's birth. Bodhisattva Siddhartha, who has accumulated merit through countless lifetimes, attained enlightenment and
Phật Đản sinh Bồ Tát Tất Đạt Đa
reached the final stage of his life. Upon his birth, his
đau Bồ Đề đến kiếp cuối cùng khi vừa đàn
heart was pure and youthful, his head adorned with lotus blossoms, and his heels like lotus flowers.
sinh lòng trắng trẻ đầu hoa sen lưng gót
[Music]
[âm nhạc]
Following the Footsteps of the Pure Heart, we
Theo Bước Chân Tâm Đoan chúng con nhiều
rejoice in the Buddha's birth. We ask the Bodhisattva to go
mừng Đức Phật
east, to guide all
về phương đông Làm Người Dẫn đường cho
beings towards the south, cultivating
bao chúng sinh hướng về phương Nam làm
fields of merit, singing in the realm of humans and
ruộng phước lành hát chốn nhân thiên
gods, and returning to the west, writing the final
hương về phương Tây là viết cuối cùng
chapter of the Bodhisattva's path, lingering in the clouds
hạnh Bồ Tát đạo hướng về vương vấn mây
of this lifetime.
trong kiếp này
At that time, the Buddha,
Chừng đó Phật Quan
following the Footsteps of the Pure Heart, we
Theo Bước Chân Tâm Đoan chúng con nhiều
rejoice in the Buddha's birth. We ask the
mừng Đức Phật đã xin Bồ Tát
Bodhisattva to point to the heavens, to guide the noble celestial beings, to
chỉ trời làm cho quý thiên nhân sâu nẻo
place his hand upon the ambush of demons, the lineage of immortal
một tay chỉ đặt trên phục binh ma dòng
lions, the heavens above and below, the only supreme being
tiên sư tử Thiên Thượng Thiên Hạ Duy ngã
from the void, the stream of
độc tôn từ nơi hư không hỡi dòng nước
compassion, once a year, the mind is pure and compassionate.
thương một năm một lần tâm thần thái từ
[Music]
[âm nhạc]
Commemorating the Buddha's birth, we
kỷ niệm ngày Đức Phật Đản sinh chúng con
follow in his footsteps, rejoicing in the Buddha's
theo bước chân từng đoạn nhiều mừng Đức
birth. Bodhisattva Siddhartha
Phật Đản sinh
[Music]
[âm nhạc]
Following the Footsteps of the Pure Heart  We
Theo Bước Chân Tâm Đoan chúng con nhiều
rejoice greatly at the Buddha's arrival. We ask the Bodhisattva to
mừng Đức Phật
guide the heavens, making the poor and
chỉ trời làm cho quý thiên nhân sau
needy a single hand to pacify the demons in a moment. The
nghèo một tay chỉ đơn trên phút bình ma
lineage of the lion-like celestial beings, the Heavenly Lion, the Supreme One,
dòng tiên sư tử Thiên Thượng Thiên Hạ
from the void or the flowing
Duy ngã độc tôn từ nơi hư không hay dòng
water, once a year, bathing in divine grace
nước kia một năm Một lần tắm thần thái
from
từ
before the house, the chrysanthemum flowers bloom.
trước nhà thì dài hoa cúc
We, your children, rejoice in the
đoàn chúng con yêu mừng trong con cá
individuality of this day. The flowing
tính một ngày Đông phận
water, the long-lasting flower offerings,
chưa Thuyên Trôi nhạc dài hoa cúng dường
also become a blessing. The people sing in celebration, following the
cũng thành Dân Trí hát mừng Reo Ca theo
footsteps of the monastic
bước chân
community. We rejoice, we
tăng đoàn chúng con yêu mừng chúng con
have
có
good news on the day of the Buddha.
tin mừng ngày Đức Phật
[music]
[âm nhạc]